<resources>
    <string name="app_name">FYP</string>
    <string name="sign_up">Sign Up</string>
    <string name="log_in">Log In</string>
    <string name="program">FYP</string>
    <string name="home">This is an Educational based trading platform with short term predictions for stocks, developed as part of the coursework.</string>

    <string name="mains">
        This is a home page, where you can log out.
        The next page is search page, where you can type your question.
        On the next page, you can explore different trading strategies.
        The fourth page is for checking current stock market, possible predictions and buy/sell options.
        The last page is to view previous positions and close any opened.</string>

    <string name="strategy_1">A news trading strategy involves trading based on news and market expectations, both before and following news releases.
        Trading on news announcements can require a skilled mind-set as news can travel very quickly on digital media.
        Traders will need to assess the news immediately after it’s released and make a quick judgement on how to trade it.
        Some key considerations include: Is the news already fully factored into the price of an instrument or only partially priced in? Does the news match market expectations?
        Understanding these differences in market expectations is crucial to success when using a news trading strategy.</string>
    <string name="strategy_12">When trading based on news releases, it’s vital that the trader is aware of how financial markets operate.
        Markets need energy to move and this comes from information flow such as news releases. Therefore, it’s common that news is already factored into the assets price.
        This results from traders attempting to predict the results of future news announcements and in turn, the market’s response.
        A news trading strategy is particularly useful for volatile markets, including when trading oil and other fluctuating commodities.</string>

    <string name="strategy_2">The end-of-day (EOD) trading strategy involves trading near the close of markets.
        EOD traders become active when it becomes clear that the price is going to ‘settle’ or close.
        This strategy requires the studying of price action in comparison to the previous day’s price movements.
        EOD traders can then speculate how the price could move based on the price action and decide on any indicators that they are using in their system.</string>
    <string name="strategy_22">Traders should create a set of risk management orders including a limit order, a stop-loss order and a take-profit order to reduce any overnight risk.
        This style of trading requires less time commitment than other trading strategies. This is because there is only a need to study charts at their
        opening and closing times.</string>

    <string name="strategy_3">The term ‘swing trading refers to trading both sides on the movements of any financial market. Swing traders aim to ‘buy’ a
        security when they suspect that the market will rise. Otherwise, they can ‘sell’ an asset when they suspect that the price will fall.
        Swing traders take advantage of the market’s oscillations as the price swings back and forth, from an overbought to oversold state.
        Swing trading is purely a technical approach to analysing markets, achieved through studying charts and analysing the individual movements that
        comprise a bigger picture trend.</string>
    <string name="strategy_32">Successful swing trading relies on the interpretation of the length and duration of each swing, as these define important
        support and resistance levels. Additionally, swing traders will need to identify trends where the markets encounter increasing levels of supply or demand.
        Traders also consider if momentum is increasing or decreasing within each swing while monitoring trades.</string>

    <string name="strategy_4">Intraday trading is suitable for traders that would like to actively trade in the daytime, generally as a full time profession.
        They take advantage of price fluctuations in-between the market open and close hours, often holding multiple positions, but do not leave positions open
        overnight in order to minimise the risk of overnight market volatility. It’s recommended that these types of traders follow an organised trading plan that
        can quickly adapt to fast market movements.</string>
    <string name="strategy_42">Just before the open of the FTSE and other European markets, traders should look to study the support and resistance levels and the possible
        reactions to the previous night’s trading in the US, as well as moves that have occurred in the Far Eastern markets. Many traders look to trade European markets
        in the first two hours when there is high liquidity. Otherwise, traders usually focus between 12pm – 5pm GMT when both the UK and US markets are open.</string>

    <string name="strategy_5">This strategy describes when a trader uses technical analysis to define a trend, and only enters trades in the direction of the pre-determined
        trend.

        ‘The trend is your friend’

        The above is a famous trading motto and one of the most accurate in the markets. Following the trend is different from being ‘bullish or bearish’.
        Trend traders do not have a fixed view of where the market should go or in which direction. Success in trend trading can be defined by having an accurate system
        to firstly determine and then follow trends. However, it’s crucial to stay alert and adaptable as the trend can quickly change. Trend traders need to be aware of
        the risks of market reversals, those which can be mitigated with a trailing stop-loss order.</string>
    <string name="strategy_52">Several trend-following tools can be used for analysing specific markets including equities, treasuries, currencies and commodities.
        Trend traders will need to exercise their patience as ‘riding the trend’ can be difficult. However, with enough confidence in their trading system, the trend trader
        should be able to stay disciplined and follow their rules. However, it’s equally important to know when your system has stopped working. This usually occurs due to
        a fundamental market change, therefore it’s important to cut your losses short and let your profits run when trend trading.</string>

    <string name="strategy_6">Traders who use a scalping strategy place very short-term trades with small price movements. Scalpers aim to ‘scalp’ a small profit from
        each trade in the hope that all the small profits accumulate. As a scalper, you must have a disciplined exit strategy as a large loss can eliminate many other
        profits that have accumulated slow and steadily.</string>
    <string name="strategy_62">A scalper would operate away from the common mantra “let your profits run”, as scalpers tend to take their profits before the market
        has a chance to move. As scalpers generally operate on a risk/reward ratio of around 1/1, it’s common for scalpers not to make a large profit per trade,
        instead focusing on increasing their total number of smaller winning trades. Scalping is particularly common when trading currency pairs, so learn how to scalp forex.</string>

    <string name="strategy_7">Position trading is a popular trading strategy where a trader holds a position for a long period of time, usually months or years,
        ignoring minor price fluctuations in favor of profiting from long-term trends. Position traders tend to use fundamental analysis to evaluate potential price
        trends within the markets, but also take into considerations other factors such as market trends and historical patterns.</string>
    <string name="strategy_72">-</string>

    <string name="stock_market">The stock market is a platform where public companies sell shares of their ownership to the public.
        It is a marketplace where stocks or shares of publicly-traded companies are bought and sold. Investors can buy and sell stocks through a stock exchange,
        such as the New York Stock Exchange (NYSE) or NASDAQ. The stock market provides companies with a way to raise capital by selling shares, and investors with
        a way to profit from the growth of those companies. The value of stocks is influenced by a variety of factors, including company performance,
        economic conditions, and investor sentiment.
    The stock market is a platform where public companies sell shares of their ownership to the public.
        It is a marketplace where stocks or shares of publicly-traded companies are bought and sold. Investors can buy and sell stocks through a stock exchange,
        such as the New York Stock Exchange (NYSE) or NASDAQ. The stock market provides companies with a way to raise capital by selling shares, and investors with
        a way to profit from the growth of those companies. The value of stocks is influenced by a variety of factors, including company performance,
        economic conditions, and investor sentiment.</string>

    <string name="p_information">In trading, positions refer to the ownership or holdings of financial instruments by traders or investors. A position represents the
        quantity and type of assets held in a portfolio at a specific time. It can be either long or short. A long position involves buying an asset with the
        expectation that its value will increase, while a short position involves selling an asset that is not currently owned, with the intention of buying it back
        at a lower price. Position sizes vary based on the number of units held. Monitoring and managing positions are crucial aspects of trading, as traders make decisions
        to buy or sell based on market conditions and their strategies, aiming to optimize their risk-reward profile.</string>

    <string name="forex">Forex, short for foreign exchange, refers to the global decentralized market where currencies are traded. It is the largest and most liquid
        financial market, with participants including banks, financial institutions, corporations, governments, and individual traders. Forex trading involves the
        buying and selling of currency pairs, where one currency is exchanged for another at an agreed-upon price. Traders in the forex market aim to profit from
        fluctuations in currency exchange rates by speculating on whether a currency will appreciate or depreciate relative to another. Factors such as economic indicators,
        geopolitical events, and market sentiment influence currency movements. Forex trading operates 24 hours a day, five days a week, allowing for continuous trading
        opportunities across different time zones. Traders can leverage margin and employ various strategies, including technical analysis, fundamental analysis, and
        algorithmic trading, to participate in the forex market.</string>

    <string name="trading">Trading refers to the buying and selling of financial instruments, such as stocks, bonds, commodities, currencies, or derivatives,
        with the aim of generating profits from price fluctuations. Traders actively participate in various markets, utilizing their knowledge, analysis, and strategies
        to take advantage of short-term opportunities. Trading can be done by individuals, institutions, or specialized firms, and it involves making decisions based on
        market trends, technical indicators, fundamental analysis, and other factors. Different trading styles exist, including day trading, swing trading, position
        trading, and algorithmic trading. The ultimate goal of trading is to generate returns by accurately predicting and capitalizing on price movements in order to
        buy low and sell high or sell high and buy low. However, trading also carries inherent risks, and proper risk management and discipline are essential for long-term
        success in the trading arena.</string>

</resources>